Lakshmi Vasantha Chandrapati

Phone number: 9845058446 • Email address: LakshmiVasanthaCh@gmail.com

Certified Product Owner with 17+ years of experience in building the products within time, budget & quality parameters, targeting senior-level assignments in Product Management with an organization of high repute.

Work Experience

06/2019 – present Bengaluru, India Product Manager symplr Healthcare Private Limited (Acquired the Workforce Management from GE Healthcare)

01/2016 — 05/2019 Bengaluru, India

Product Owner Siemens Healthineers Pvt Ltd.

- Product ownership, feature delivery, stakeholder management, customer engagement, requirements analysis, and maintenance of products.
- Defining business requirements while managing risks to improve business processes and formulating requirements into the system by preparing functional specifications & associated test requirements
- Mapping the clinical measurements and calculations using Dicom Standard (DCM, SNOMED, LOINC codes) to make them automatically available in PACS systems.
- Implementing product strategies & roadmaps to maximise success and minimise business disruption, that increased product quality and releases.
- Discussing the development & test strategy of requirements in requirement review meetings with the Product Management team and Usability Experts
- Prioritizing backlog, defining the stories, providing clarifications to assist the team with their story estimates & sprint loading, and drafting team's specific objectives for each internal release
- Incorporating feedback from customers into new & existing products
- Coordinating with other Product Owners on content dependencies and managing inter-team dependencies in respective sprints
- Providing thought leadership and technical consulting in defining, implementing, ensuring, measuring and continuous improvement of Agile methodologies along with quality standards, frameworks, practices and measurements

06/2004 — 12/2015 Bengaluru, India

Scrum Master | Team Manager | Technical Lead | Sr Software Developer | Software Developer | Siemens Healthineers Pvt Ltd.

- Defined project scope, goals & deliverables that support business goals in collaboration with senior management & stakeholders
- Led various project related activities involving project planning, execution & management in tune with the core business objectives (including risk management, effort / time / cost estimation in terms of resource availability)
- Mitigated risks and planned for contingencies to ensure minimal effect on deliverables
- Drove overall application development strategy and worked with business leadership teams for assigned products/applications
- Optimized resource pyramids, utilized capacity, forecasted workload, and ensured the collaborative implementation of best practices
- Developed & integrated critical algorithms for cardiac calculations on SC2000 Ultrasound System
- Acted as Single Point of Contact for the technical coordination between onshore and offshore team
- Provided design decisions related to measurements & report integration to SC2000 Ultrasound Scanner from offshore.
- Developed User Interface & Modules for Siemens Ultrasound Scanners and Standalone Applications to troubleshoot complex components.

Achievements

- Received symplr Quarterly award for driving two Mobile initiatives in parallel successfully.
- Siemens STAR Award in 2016 for delivering DICOM mappings for thousands of measurements supported by Compass Ultrasound System which was the state of the art project compared to competitors as per business need,
- Attained Siemens STAR Award in 2014 for gaining customer confidence in bringing back the project on track as Team Manager.
- Got nominated for Siemens Business Excellence Awards (Expert Category) by Business Head, India in 2015.
- Spearheaded 3 concurrent projects as Scrum Master with teams of 8 to 14 members
- Facilitated transition from primarily Waterfall to Agile development methodology that resulted in benefits such as early releases of assigned modules with the agreed quality metrics.
- Lead one of the business segments to drive adoption of Lean and Agile practices across 50+ employees; working
 with executives to foster a change-friendly environment, resulting in improved collaboration and transparency.
- Received Star Award in 2012 for developing Structured Reporting Verification Tool for SC2000 Structured Reporting Component.
- Led the Development Teams for go-live of advanced Healthcare Applications in collaboration with cross-functional teams across the globe
- Appreciated for smooth transfer of key projects from other development sites to Bangalore Development Centre

Skills

– CORE SKILLS Product Management	Requirements analysis & Research
Stakeholder Management	Project Management
Agile Methodologies	Team Management

Certificates

Certified Product Owner

Certified Scrum Master

Participated in Siemens Lean Development Expert Program

Participated in Siemens Project Management Program

Participated in Siemens Leadership Program

Education

06/2000 – 04/2002 Computer Science | M.Sc. Acharya Nagarjuna University

06/1994 – 04/1997 **Computer Science | B.Sc.**

Acharya Nagarjuna University